sorbets are absolutely delicious but
usually loaded with added sugar and
unnecessary calories not to mention
these pints aren't just one serving so
those added calories will add to your
waistline quick in today's video i will
be showing you three perfect summertime
sorbet recipes that are under 100
calories for the entire pint only take
three ingredients to make and once you
have the fruit juice take just 90
seconds to prep and i suggest staying
until the end of the video because i
saved the best for last let's get into
it
for this we will need well a watermelon
making sure you get a good watermelon is
important sweet and juicy watermelons
usually have a deep yellowish
orange spot on it from where it was
sitting in the field and are dark and
dull oh and make sure it's seedless to
save yourself some hassle wash it dry it
and put it on the biggest cutting board
you have by the way everything i used
will be linked in the description below
in case you want to check it out grab
your knife and cut the ends off while
trying to cut as little flesh or pink
part off as possible the pink part holds
that sweet sweet nectar that we want one
of the ends will have less rind than the
other which i got on first try the
thicker side took me a couple tries to
get down to the flesh but i'd rather
slice off too little than too much then
cut your watermelon in half and put it
off to the side place the other half
flesh side down on the cutting board cut
where the pink meets the white or the
rind and try to follow that all the way
down again trying not to cut too much of
the flesh off go around the entire
watermelon until you don't see any more
white but if a little rind remains
that's okay now start on one end of the
flesh and make cuts every half inch to
inch now a little farther apart is okay
we just want to get them in smaller
chunks that will fit in the blender then
turn your cutting board 90 degrees and
repeat the other way grab a food
processor or blender and fill it up with
the watermelon blend for about 30
seconds or until everything is broken
down now if you can't fit all the
watermelon in one batch which you
probably won't be able to unless you
have a gigantic blender dump your
blended juice into the containers you
will store it in then refill the blender
personally i love these containers
because they are stackable and come in a
bunch of different sizes but you can use
whatever containers that you'd like get
all of your fresh watermelon juice
stored and ready to use this process
will undoubtedly be a little bit messy
so once you are done cleaning off your
workstation grab one of your containers
of juice a scale and a creamy pint you
will notice your watermelon has
separated so right before you pour it
into the pint give it a mix put the pint
on the scale and weigh out 330 grams of
watermelon 120 grams of water 20 grams
of urethra tall and a half gram of salt
personally i love urethra tall and use
it for everything but if you don't like
it or have another sweetener on hand
feel free to use it keep in mind every
sweetener is different and has variable
sweetness so try your sorbet before you
put it in the freezer it should be
sweeter than you would like because when
things are served frozen the flavor is
dulled or decreased also the half gram
of salt helps bring out sweetness so
don't skip this ingredient after
everything is added to your pint mix
with a hand blender or one of these
blender thingies i got from pe science
for about 30 seconds you can use the
full size blender or food processor to
do this but this means you have to use
and clean a big accessory every time you
want to make a sorbet once you have the
watermelon pureed a smaller appliance is
much more convenient because it is easy
to grab and go and can be washed in
about 10 seconds add a lid to your
sorbet and store it in the freezer for
24 hours now i have done about 16 hours
and feel like i got the exact same
results but ninja says 24 so to be safe
you should do 24. the next day take your
pint and run it under lukewarm to
moderately hot water for 60 seconds and
yes i time it i highly suggest you do
too because you think you have ran it
for a minute but it's only been 30
seconds trust me i am guilty of it this
process will almost completely take away
any ice on the sides of the pint that
may be left over that the blade in the
creamy doesn't get to then take your
pint load it up and let it run on the
sorbet option when finished i don't even
look at it and run it for a re-spin
however let's see what we get after one
spin it is still very crumbly and
doesn't look nearly ready yet load it
back up and respin it once that is
finished you will notice the outside of
the pint looks ready but the middle is
still crumbly and needs some more creamy
lovin at this point i found taking a
spoon and using the backside to rub
everything smooth and leveling it off
again was the best way to go this helps
everything get combined and ready for
the last spin re-spin one more time when
it's done it should have a perfect
sorbet consistency that reminds me so
much of the best italian ice i have ever
had called freddy's because they are so
rich and smooth it reminds me of its
sorbet counterpart our sorbet has body a
super smooth mouth feel and is perfectly
sweet with a punch of real watermelon
flavor just an fyi the water i initially
bought made 15 pints and at four dollars
a watermelon is an absolute steal on a
per pint basis let's move on to the dark
horse flavor cantaloupe many of the
steps are very similar to that of the
watermelon so we are going to run
through this one wash your cantaloupe
dry your cantaloupe and get your
cantaloupe on a cutting board cut a thin
layer off of each end exposing the flesh
and then cut it in half scoop the seeds
out of the middle with a spoon and lay
your cantaloupe middle side down then
carefully cut the outside layer of the
rind off keep in mind the skin on a
cantaloupe is much thinner than a
watermelon so your slices won't need to
be nearly as thick when all you see is
the color orange cut it exactly like the
watermelon and use your crushing machine
of choice to get it down to a puree i
will use a food processor while it's
blending feel free to enjoy the fruits
of your labor by enjoying a slice or two
of fresh cantaloupe when your juice is
ready pour your cantaloupe into a
container then pour 300 grams into your
pint along with 160 grams of water 20
grams of erythritol and a half gram of
salt give it a spin for about 30 seconds
to get everything combined and throw it
into the freezer after 24 hours grab
your cantaloupe ice block and run it
under water for 60 seconds lock it into
place hit that sorbet button and then
respin it twice to get that real sorbet
consistency remember to level everything
out with a spoon between the two respins
i now welcome you to the best cantaloupe
sorbet you never knew you needed by the
way if you want recipes like this that
help keep the calories low while still
enjoying your diet i can help using my
10 years of experience and masters in
exercise physiology i write customized
training and meal plans and do
one-on-one coaching that is specifically
tailored to you so if eating the foods
you love while losing weight interests
you click the top link in the
description below we saved the best for
last and that is strawberry grab a pound
of strawberries rinse them and cut off
the ends i cut off as little as i can
which is just enough to get the root and
leaves off for this recipe i'm going to
use an immersion blender to puree the
strawberries so you can see the plethora
of options you have to get to the same
final destination after each strawberry
is cut throw them inside of your creamy
pint which is already on the scale once
we hit 300 grams we will stop and add
130 grams of water 20 grams of
erythritol and a half gram of salt put
your immersion blender into the pint and
puree it for about 60 to 90 seconds or
until well combined put a cap on it and
throw it in the freezer for 24 hours as
usual rinse off the sides and bottom for
60 seconds lock into place and hit that
sorbet button if you look at the pint
after one blend you will see it looks
pretty close to done most likely because
of the pectin and the strawberries
giving the sorbet a ton of body however
it could use another re-spin so lock it
into place and give it a go you will
notice the consistency of this one is
almost ice cream like without any dairy
whatsoever and the fact that it's just
under 100 calories is absolutely
mind-boggling at the end of the day
whichever flavor you choose to make will
be bursting with flavor the freshest
sorbet you will ever eat and you will
know exactly what's in it i highly
suggest you make one and report back
with your findings in the meantime here
is an oreo mcflurry recipe you might be
interested in if you want a little more
volume it tastes exactly like an oreo
mcflurry from mcdonald's and the
hundreds of people that have tried it
agree until next time deuces